http://www.netcomposites.com/privacy-policy/

Categories
LATEST NEWS:
Gardner Business Media Acquires NetComposites Media Assets 10 months ago
NetComposites Ltd has transferred the rights and ownership of this website to Gardner Business Media Inc.
On 1st January 2020, NetComposites' media assets including netcomposites.com, newsletters and conferences were transferred to Composites World (Gardner Business Media).
This site is no longer being updated. Please direct all enquiries to netcomposites@gardnerweb.com.
For further details see our joint press release.
NetComposites > Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Who we are and important information
This is the privacy notice of NetComposites Ltd.
We respect your privacy and are determined to protect your personal data. The purpose of this privacy notice is to inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from). We’ll also tell you about your privacy rights and how the data protection law protects you.
What is the purpose of this privacy notice?
This privacy notice aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you make an enquiry, request information, or purchase one of our training courses. This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.
You must read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.
Data controller
NetComposites Ltd is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “NetComposites”,, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice). Our contact details are 4A Broom Business Park, Bridge Way, Chesterfield, Derbyshire, S41 9QG, UK, +44 (0)1246 266244. For all data matters contact our data representative using these details.
Third-party links outside of our control
This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.
When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
The personal data we collect about you
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. You can find out more about personal data from the Information Commissioners Office.
We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:
Identity Data includes title, first name, last name and job titleContact Data includes organisation, billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers
We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.
We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.
If you fail to provide personal data
Where we need to collect your personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.
How we collect your personal data
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
You may give us your Identity or Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes the personal data you provide when you:
Register as a user for the website online communityPurchase digital advertisingEnquire about our products or servicesRequest information to be sent to you such as the weekly newsletter, media offerings or information about NetComposites events
How we use your personal data
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
Performance of Contract – this means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.Legitimate Interest – this means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation – this means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
Purposes for which we will use your personal data
This is a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, with the legal bases we rely on to do so.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/ActivityType of dataLawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interestTo respond to an enquiry received via a “Contact Us” enquiry form on the website(a) Identity(b) ContactResponding to an enquiry that you have raised about our offerings.To opt you into selected marketing information services at your request via the form on the website(a) Identity(b) ContactResponding to your expression of interest to receive our marketing information.To process an order for one of our media offerings(a) Identity(b) Contact Performance of a contract with you.To register you as a user for our online community(a) Identity(b) ContactResponding to your request to register as a user of our website.
Marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly for marketing and advertising.
Promotional offers from us
We may use your Identity and Contact Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant to you.
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us.
Opting out
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by updating your marketing preferences on the website or by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by emailing data.protection@netcomposites.com at any time.
Cookies
You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our cookie policy.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact our data representative on +44 (0)1246 266246 or data.protection@netcomposites.com.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
Who we share your personal data with
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.
External third party servicesProviders of IT and system administration servicesProfessional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide banking, legal, insurance and accounting servicesHM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstancesThird parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
International transfers
Some of our external third-party IT and system administration providers may be based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data may involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.
Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
Data retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
For audit and accounting purposes,  we may have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for up to ten years after they cease being customers.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Your legal rights below for further information.
In some circumstances, we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
Your legal rights
Unless subject to an exemption under the data protection laws, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
The right to request a copy of the personal data which we hold about you;The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary to retain such data;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time, where consent was the lawful basis for processing your data;The right to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), where applicable i.e. where our processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of our contract with you or where we process your data by automated means);The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;The right to object to our processing of personal data, where applicable i.e. where processing is based on our legitimate interests.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact our data representative on +44 (0)1246 266246 or data.protection@netcomposites.com.
No fee required – with some exceptions
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable admin fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
What we may need from you
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
Time limit to respond
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
Changes to this notice and your duty to inform us of changes
This version was last updated on 27th June 2019.
Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current.
Queries, requests or concerns
To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints in relation to this policy or any other data protection matter between you and us, please in the first instance contact our data representative on +44 (0)1246 266246 or data.protection@netcomposites.com.
If this does not resolve your complaint to your satisfaction, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF, England, UK.
Upcoming Events
Latest News
Gardner Business Media Acquires NetComposites Media Assets
14th February 2020
Newest Composites Questions
0
how to calculate fiber-matrix weight percentage from given density?
1
how to calculate the theoretical fiber volume fraction
0
Are there any health concerns regarding use of nanocomposites?
Follow us
This website uses cookies to improve user experience. By using our website you consent to all cookies in accordance with our Cookie PolicyOkay, thank you
